In this video, we're gonna begin our discussion of parsing technology with
在本视频中，我们将从以下内容开始讨论解析技术
context-free grammars. Now as we know, not all strings of tokens are actually valid
上下文无关文法。现在我们知道，并不是所有的标记字符串都是有效的
programs and the parser has to tell the difference. It has to know which strings
程序和解析器必须分辨出不同之处。它必须知道哪些字符串
of tokens are valid and which ones are invalid and give error messages for the
的令牌是有效的，哪些是无效的，并给出
invalid ones. So, we need some way of describing the valid strings of tokens and
无效的。因此，我们需要某种方式来描述有效的令牌字符串和
then some kind of algorithm for distinguishing the valid and invalid
然后给出一种区分有效和无效的算法
strings of tokens from each other. Now we've also discussed that programming
来自彼此的一串串代币。现在我们还讨论了编程
languages have a natural recursive structure, So for example in Cool, an
语言有一种自然的递归结构，例如在Cool中，
expression That can be anyone of a very large number of things. So two of the
可以是大量事物中的任何一个的表达式。所以有两个
things that can be are an if expression and a while expression but these
可以是IF表达式和WHILE表达式，但这些
expressions are themselves recursively composed of other expressions. So for
表达式本身由其他表达式递归组成。所以对于
example, the predicate of an if is a, a [inaudible] expression as is the then
例如，IF的谓词是一个[听不见的]表达式，就像THEN一样
branch and the else branch and in a while loop the termination test is an expression
分支和Else分支，在WHILE循环中，终止测试是一个表达式
and so is the loop body. And context-free grammars are in natural notation for
循环体也是如此。而上下文无关文法是以自然符号表示的
describing such recursive structures. So within a context-free grammar so formally
描述这种递归结构。所以在如此正式的上下文无关文法中
it consist a set of terminals t, a set of nonterminals n, a start symbol s and s is
它由一组终端t、一组非终端n、开始符号s和s是
one of the nonterminals and a set of productions and what's a production? A
其中一个非终端和一套产品，什么是产品？一个
production is a symbol followed by an arrow followed by a list of symbols. And
产品是一个符号，后跟一个箭头和一个符号列表。和
these symbols, there are certain rules about them so the x thing on the left hand
这些符号，有一定的规则，所以左手上的x
side of the arrow has to be a nonterminal. That's what it means to be on the left
箭头的一侧必须是非终端。这就是站在左边的意义所在
hand side so the set of things on the left hand side of productions are exactly the
所以产品左边的那组东西正好是
nonterminals. And then the right hand side every yi on the right hand side can be
非终端。然后在右手边，右手边的每个彝族人都可以
either a nonterminal or it can be a terminal or it can be the special symbol
可以是非终端，也可以是终端，也可以是特殊符号
epsilon. So let's do a simple example of a Context-free Grammar. Strings of balanced
埃普西隆。让我们做一个上下文无关文法的简单例子。平衡字符串
parenthesis which we discussed in an earlier video can be expressed as follows.
我们在前面的视频中讨论的括号可以表示如下。
So, we have our start symbol and. One possibility for a string o f balanced
所以我们有我们的开始符号和。平衡字符串的一种可能性
parentheses is that it consists of an open paren on another string of balanced
括号是由另一个平衡字符串上的左帕伦组成的
parentheses and a close paren. And, the other possibility for a string of balanced
圆括号和接近的帕伦。而且，另一种可能性是一串平衡的
parentheses that is empty because the empty string is also a string of balanced
括号为空，因为空字符串也是平衡的字符串
parentheses. So, there are two productions for this grammar and just to go over the
括号。因此，这个语法有两个结果，我们来回顾一下
to, to relate this example to the formal definition we gave on the previous slide,
为了把这个例子和我们在上一张幻灯片上给出的正式定义联系起来，
what is our set of nine terminals, it's just. The singles nonterminal s, what our
我们的九个终端是什么，它只是。单打非终结者，我们的
terminal symbols in this context-free grammar is just open and close paren. No
在这个上下文无关文法中，末尾符号只是打开和关闭Paren。不是的
other symbols. What's the start symbol? Well, it's s. It's the only nonterminal so
其他符号。开始符号是什么？嗯，是s。这是唯一的非终点站
it has to be the start symbol but generally we will, when we give grammars
它必须是开始符号，但通常情况下，当我们给出语法时，我们会这样做
the first production will name a start symbol so rather than name and explicitly
第一个产品将这样命名一个开始符号，而不是明确地命名和
whichever production occurs first the symbol on the left hand side will be the
无论哪个产品首先发生，左侧的符号都将是
nonterminal for that particular context-free grammar. And then finally,
该特定上下文无关文法的非终止符。然后最后，
what are the productions with the, we said there could be a set of productions and
有什么制作，我们说可以有一套制作，
here are the two productions for this particular Context-Free Grammar. Now,
下面是这个特定的上下文无关文法的两个成果。现在,
productions can be read as rules. So, let's write down one of our productions
产品可以理解为规则。那么，让我们写下我们的一部作品
from the from the example grammar and what does this mean? This means wherever we see
根据示例语法，这是什么意思？这意味着无论我们在哪里看到
an s, we can replace it by the string of symbols on the right hand side. So,
如果是s，我们可以用右手边的符号串替换它。所以,
Wherever I see an s I can substitute and I can take the s out. If that important, I
只要我看到S，我就能买到替身，我就能把S带出去。如果这很重要，我
remove the s that appears on the left side and I replace it by the string of symbols
删除出现在左侧的s，我将其替换为符号字符串
on the right hand side so productions can be read as replacement rule so right hand
在右手边，所以乘积可以理解为替换规则，所以右手边
side replaces the left hand side. So here's a little more formal description of
侧边替换左手边。所以这里有一个更正式的描述
that process. We begin with the string that has only the start symbol s, so we
这个过程。我们从只有开始符号s的字符串开始，所以我们
always start with just the start symbol. And now, we look at our string initially
始终仅以开始符号开头。现在，我们首先看一下我们的弦
it's just a start symbol but it changes overtime, and we can replace any
这只是一个开始符号，但随着时间的推移它会改变，我们可以替换任何
non-terminal in the string by the right hand side, side of some production for
非端子在串的右手边，边上有一些为生产用的
that non-terminal. So for exam ple, I can replace a non-terminal x by the right hand
那个非终结者。例如，我可以用右手替换非终端x
side of some production for x. X in this case, x goes to y1 through yn. And then we
在这种情况下，x等于y1到yn。然后我们
just repeat step two over and over again until there are no non-terminals left
只需一遍又一遍地重复第二步，直到没有非终端
until the string consist of only terminals. And at that point, we're done.
直到字符串仅由端子组成。在这一点上，我们就完了。
So, to write this out slightly more formally, a single step here consist of a
因此，为了更正式地写出这一点，这里的单个步骤由一个
state which is a, which is a string of symbols, so this can be terminals and
状态是a，这是一个符号字符串，所以这可以是终端和
non-terminals. And, somewhere in the string is a non-terminal x and there is a
非终端。并且，字符串中的某个位置是非末尾x，并且有一个
production for x, in our grammar. So this is part of the grammar, okay? This is a
在我们的语法中，x的乘积。所以这是语法的一部分，好吗？这是一个
production And we can use now production to take a step from, to a new state Where
生产，我们可以利用现在的生产来迈出一步，从一个新的状态，到一个新的状态，
we have replaced X by the right hand side of the production, Okay? So this is one
我们已经用制作的右手边取代了X，好吗？所以这是一个
step of a context-free derivation. So now if you wanted to do multiple steps, we
上下文无关派生的步骤。所以现在如果你想做多个步骤，我们
could have a bunch of steps, alpha zero goes to alpha one goes to alpha two and
可能有一堆步骤，阿尔法0到阿尔法1，阿尔法2，然后
these are strings now. Alpha i's are all strings and as we go along we eventually
现在这些都是弦了。阿尔法i都是弦，当我们前进的时候，我们最终
get to some strong alpha n, alright. And then we say that alpha zero rewrites in
找一个强壮的阿尔法n，好的。然后我们说阿尔法零重写
zero or more steps to alpha n so this means n zero, greater than or equal to
零个或多个步长到αn，因此这意味着n为零，大于或等于
zero steps. Okay. So this is just a short hand for saying there is some sequence of
零步法。好吧。所以这只是一种速记，意思是说有一些序列
individual productions. Individual rules being applied to a string that gets us
个人作品。将单独的规则应用于一个字符串，该字符串使我们
from the string alpha string zero to the string alpha n and remember that in
从字符串alpha string 0到字符串alpha n，并记住在
general we start with just the start symbol and so we have a whole bunch of
一般说来，我们从开始符号开始，所以我们有一大堆
sequence of steps like this that get us from start symbol to some other string. So
像这样的一系列步骤，让我们从开始符号转到其他字符串。所以
finally, we can define the language of a Context-Free Grammar. So, [inaudible]
最后，我们可以定义上下文无关文法的语言。所以，[听不见]
context-free grammar has a start symbol s, so then the language of the context-free
上下文无关文法有一个起始符号s，因此语言的上下文无关性
grammar is gonna be the string of symbols alpha one through alpha n such that for
语法将是从alpha1到alphan的符号串，这样对于
all i. Alpha i is an element of the terminals of g, okay. So t here is the set
所有的i，αi都是g的终结点的一个元素，好的。那么，这就是布景。
of terminals of g and s goes, the start symbol s goes in zero or more steps to
在g和s的端子中，开始符号s在零个或多个步骤中到达
alpha one, I'm sorry a1 to an, okay. And so we're just saying, this is just saying
阿尔法一号，对不起，A1呼叫A，好的。所以我们只是在说，这只是在说
that all the strings of terminals that I can derive beginning with just the start
我可以派生的所有终端字符串都从开头开始
symbol, those are the strings in the language. So the name terminal comes from
符号，这些是语言中的字符串。所以终端这个名字来源于
the fact that once terminals are included in the string, there is no rule of
事实上，一旦字符串中包括了终端，就没有规则
replacing them. That is once the terminal is generated, it's a permanent feature of
替换它们。也就是说，一旦终端生成，它就是
the string and in applications to programming languages and context-free
字符串和在应用程序中的编程语言和上下文无关
grammars, the terminals are to be the tokens of the language that we are
语法，终端将成为我们所在语言的标志
modeling with our context-free grammar. With that in mind, let's try the
用我们的上下文无关文法建模。考虑到这一点，让我们尝试一下
context-free grammar for a fragment of [inaudible]. So, [inaudible] expressions,
[听不见]片段的上下文无关文法。所以，[听不见]表情，
we talked about these earlier, but one possibility for a [inaudible] expression
我们早些时候谈过这些，但有一种可能是[听不见的]表情
is that it's an if statement or an if expression. And, we call that [inaudible]
它是if语句还是if表达式。我们称之为[听不见]
if statements have three parts. And they end with the keyword [inaudible] which is
IF语句由三部分组成。它们以关键字[听不见]结束，该关键字是
a little bit unusual. And so looking at this looking at this particular rule, we
有点不寻常。所以看看这个，看看这条特殊的规则，我们
can see some conventions that way, that are pretty standard and that we'll use so
我可以这样看一些约定，它们是非常标准的，我们将使用
that non-terminals are in all caps. Okay, so in this case was just [inaudible] we'll
非终结符都是大写的。好的，所以在这种情况下我们只是[听不见]
try that in caps and then the terminal symbols are in, in lower case, all right?
试着用大写字母写，然后终端符号就是小写的，好吗？
And another possibility Is that it could be a while expression. And finally the
另一种可能性是，它可能是一个While表达式。最后是
last possibility Is that it could be identifier id and there actually many,
最后一种可能性是它可以是标识符ID并且实际上有许多，
many more possibilities and lots of other cases for expressions and let me just show
表达式有更多的可能性和更多的其他情况，让我来展示一下
you one bit of notation to make things look a little bit nicer. So we have many
你只要做一点记号，就能让东西看起来好一点。所以我们有很多
we have many productions for the same non-terminal. We usually group those
我们有很多同一种非终端机的产品。我们通常把那些
together in the grammar and we only write a non-terminal on the right hand side once
一起在语法中使用，我们只在右边写一次非终结符
and then we write explicit alternative. So this is actually. Completely the same as
然后我们写出显式的替代方案。所以这实际上是。完全相同于
writing out expert arrow two more times but we here we just is, this is just a way
又写了两次专家箭头，但是我们在这里我们只是，这只是一种方式
of grouping these three productions together and saying that expr- is the
将这三部作品组合在一起，并说Expr-是
non-terminal for all three right hand sides. Let's take a look at some of the
所有三个右手边均为非终端。让我们来看看一些
strings on the language of this Context- Free Grammar. So, a valid Kuhl expression
此上下文无关文法的语言上的字符串。因此，有效的Kuhl表达式
is just a single identifier and that's easy to see because EXPR is our start
只有一个标识符，这很容易看到，因为expr是我们的起点
symbol, I'll call it EXPR. And, so the production it does says it goes to id. So
符号，我称它为Expr。所以，它的制作说明它是给id的。所以
I can take the start symbol directly to a string of terminals, a single variable
我可以将开始符号直接带到一个终端字符串，即单个变量
name is a valid Kuhl expression. Another example is an e-th expression where e-th
名称是有效的Kuhl表达式。另一个示例是第e个表达式，其中e-
of the subexpressions is just a variable name. So this is perfectly fine structure
子表达式的名称只是一个变量名。所以这是一个完美的结构
for a Kuhl expression. Similarly I can do the same thing with the while expression.
用于Kuhl表达式。类似地，我可以使用WHILE表达式做同样的事情。
I can take the structure of a while and then replace each of the subexpressions
我可以采用While的结构，然后替换每个子表达式
just with a single variable name and that would be a syntactically valid cool while
只有一个变量名，这在语法上是有效的
loop. There are more complicated expressions so for example, here we have a
循环。还有更复杂的表达式，例如，这里有一个
why loop as the predicate of an if expression. That's something you might
WHINE循环作为IF表达式的谓词。这是你可能会做的事
normally think or writing but perfectly well form and tactically. Similarly, I
正常的思考或写作，但形式和战术都很好。同样，我
could have an if statement or an if expression as the predicate of and if it's
可以使用IF语句或IF表达式作为AND的谓词，如果
inside of an if expression. So, so nested if expressions like this one are also
IF表达式内部。所以，如果像这样的表达式也是嵌套的
syntactically valid. Let's do another grammar, this time for simple arithmetic
句法上有效。让我们来做另一个语法，这一次是简单的算术
expressions. So, we'll have our start symbol and only non-terminal for this
表情。因此，我们将有我们的开始符号，并且这是唯一的非终止符号
grammar be called e and one of the possibilities while e could be the sum of
语法称为e，这是一种可能性，而e可以是
expressions. Or and remember this is an alternative notation for e arrow. It's
表情。或者记住，这是e箭头的另一种表示法。它是
just a way of saying I'm going to use the nonterminal for another production. We can
这只是一种说法，我要用非终端来制作另一部作品。我们可以的
have a sum of two expressions or we could have the Multiplication of two
有两个表达式的和，或者我们可以有两个表达式的乘法
expressions. And then we could have expressions that appear inside the
表情。然后我们可以让表达式出现在
parentheses, so parenthesized expressions. And just to keep things simple, we could
括号，所以用括号括起表达式。为了简单起见，我们可以
just have as our base, only base case simple identifier so variable names. And
只是有了我们的基础，才有了基础简单的标识符这样的变量名。和
here's a small grammar over plus and times to see and in parentheses and variable
下面是一个关于加号和乘法的小语法，可以在括号和变量中查看
names. [inaudible] a few elements of this language. So for example, a single
名字。[听不见]这种语言的一些元素。举个例子，一个单一的
variable name is a perfectly good element of the language id + id is also in this
变量名是语言id+id的完美元素
language. Which s is id + id id and we could also use parens to group things so
语言。哪个s是id+id id，我们也可以使用括号来分组，这样
we could say id + id id that's also something you can generate using these
我们可以说id+id id，这也是您可以使用这些
rules and so on and so forth. There are many, many more strings in this language.
规则等等。在这种语言中有很多很多的字符串。